BRANDES MOORE

Data Analyst & Finance Professional

CONTACT DETAILS

□ (615) 630 1406



brandes.moore20@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/brandesmoore

0

github.com/brandesmoore

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I'm a Data Analyst and Financial Services Leader who enjoys exploring and interpreting data, then transforming data into visualizations to drive goals and change initiatives. In addition, my leadership, healthcare, banking and equipment finance experience has allowed me to hone a variety of skills with a focus on coaching, cultivating relationships, providing excellent customer service and reducing waste, in time and the bottom line.

SKILLS AND ABILITIES

- Data Analytics Tools: Python, SQL, Tableau, Power BI
- Microsoft: Excel, Word, PowerPoint and Outlook
- Other: 6 Sigma Greenbelt, Salesforce, SAP, Moody's, LexisNexis, Agile Methodologies, Dun & Bradstreet

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School

Data Analytics Certification Expected Graduation Date: June 2020

Lipscomb University

Master of Business Administration, Finance

Tennessee State University

Bachelor's of Business Administration - Accounting

CERTIFICATIONS

Moody's Credit Risk Certified -Moody's Analytics and Investors Service, Cert. # 446

Spreadsheet Fundamentals Track -DataCamp, Credential ID: 132280

DATA EXPERIENCE

Data Analytics Apprentice Nashville Software School

2019-Present

Intensive, real-world, project management-based training in data analytics using business intelligence and visualization tools to drive business decisions.

DATA PROJECTS

Lahman Baseball (PostgreSQL)

https://github.com/brandesmoore/baseball

Analysis of baseball statistics through a database consisting of 27 tables utilizing JOINs, Window Functions and CTEs to extrapolate historical facts for comparison

- Wrote SQL queries from scratch to identify various sources of data to present to management
- · Displayed problem-solving syntax through commits, pull requests, branch and master tracking in GitHub
- · Created a data story about the shortest player in MLB history, the highest paid athlete from Vanderbilt and other statistics surrounding pitching, batting and stolen bases in the MLB from 1871-2017

Healthcare Bluebook (Python, Excel, Power BI, Tableau) https://github.com/brandesmoore/healthcarebluebook

Examination of medicare utilization and payments for providers and hospitals and to determine how claim payments have changed and which procedure(s) had the largest change in average medicare claim payment.

- Cleaned and extracted 27M rows of medicare payment data based on certain APC /HCPCS codes from 2013-2017 to review patterns and outliers
- Presented a story board to the medicare client along with a case study to determine the appropriate provider for certain APC code procedures

Metro Nashville Police Calls (Python, PowerPoint) https://github.com/brandesmoore/policecalls

Exploration of police call data to determine if crimes happen around specific times of the year and if concentrations of crimes geographically exist in certain areas within the city of Nashville

- Scraped and concatenated police call data from 2013-2018 in Python
- Created visualizations with PowerPoint to highlight police calls surrounding specific holidays showing a higher concentration in the city center

DATA CAPSTONE

How likely is it for an NCAA athlete to surpass an Olympic athlete? (Power BI) https://github.com/brandesmoore/capstone_track_and_field

A look at Individual NCAA Track & Field athletes in comparison to Olympic athletes in the same events

- Created data questions to determine the likelihood of NCAA Track & Field finishing times and distances surpassing Olympic times and distances in the same event
- Cleaned 19 tables consisting of 350+ rows of data to create a story surrounding Track & Field data at the collegiate and Olympic levels
- Wrote DAX queries to identify specific data counts from various sources
- Utilized JOINs and Appends in Power BI on multiple datasets for visualization comparisons
- Constructed a 5-7 minute virtual presentation for students, professors and potential employers highlighting the results of the project

BRANDES MOORE (CONT.)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Metropolitan Nashville Board of Education (2019-Present)

The nation's 42nd largest school district that prepares more than 86,000 students to excel in higher education, work and life.

K-12 Substitute Teacher

- Fulfill long-term vacant teaching assignments for grades K-12 by instructing students on various subject matters, with a concentration in Math & Business at the Middle and High School levels
- · Participate and lead Parent-Teacher conferences when necessary to support the students and parents in achieving academic and social balances
- · Consistently praised by school Administrators for dedication, reliability and class management skills in an understaffed district
- · Provide teaching and emotional support for up to 125 students daily by adjusting expectations for those who have academic or social challenges
- Communicate with Teachers, Administrators, Parents and Bookkeepers on enrichment programs available for students, along with the associated cost of the programs

McKesson Specialty Health (2017-2019) * Part-Time Remote*

Fortune 500 pharmaceutical and healthcare company providing credit and financial services to Physicians, hospitals and clinics

Team Lead - Senior Credit Underwriter

- 6 Sigma Green Belt SME who led a Salesforce usage roll out for tracking credit approvals, resulting in a 66.7% decrease in turnaround time after implementation across the Credit and Collections business units for the Nashville, TN and The Woodlands, TX offices
- Provided coaching, training and support to Junior Credit Analysts on career development, complex analysis and Credit Management presentations for healthcare businesses and hospitals
- Executed Credit Management presentations based on credit risk level, scope of business and pharmaceutical ordering value for Management to make decisions on extensions of additional healthcare and pharmaceutical lines of credit
- · Onboarded and assigned workflows for Junior Analysts, while providing performance feedback and training in the absence of the Support Manager
- Reviewed high priority healthcare credit submissions, while delegating additional research tasks to Junior Analysts to complete credit requests, apply
 risk ratings and make informed decisions to mitigate accounts in default

Caterpillar Financial Services (2011-2017) * Part-Time Remote*

Global financial services company offering insurance and equipment lending to construction and waste management companies

Team Lead - Credit Analyst (2015-2017)

- · Coached a team of 6 Credit Analysts responsible for the complex underwriting of commercial credit relationships
- Developed effective training manuals, best practices and an employee engagement program for a department of 50+, which reduced employee turnover by 30%
- Provided data to Sales Managers, Credit and Collections Management by reviewing client requests to determine credit worthiness and communicating
 my recommendations to the Credit Management Committee
- Mentored Junior Analysts on continuous improvement, advanced training, opportunities for promotion and building an inclusive and positive environment
- Evaluated escalated credit condition negotiations with Credit Management, direct reports and Sales Mangers for Credit Committee presentation based on credit reports, financial statement analysis, credit underwriting, loan policies and covenant compliance

Sales Support Credit Analyst (2013-2015)

- Top Performer Recipient for exceeding \$10M lease renewal sales goal within 12 months
- Collaborated with Support Manager to establish high performance standards and metric goals to support growth and development opportunities and meet service level agreements (SLAs) for a team of 27 Analysts
- Developed a team of Sales Support Analysts responsible for servicing commercial lease renewals by providing training on Lease Conversion Financing and creating web-based training modules for Onboarding new Analysts
- Provided risk-based financial product pricing and financial statement analysis along with reviews of tax returns, letters of credit, and credit bureau
 reports

Customer Collections Specialist - Cash Applications (2011-2013)

- Earned my 6 Sigma Green Belt designation and served as the SME on a default process project that eliminated 2-4 hours (25%) of processing time and decreased administration expenses by \$30K as a result of my timing of the process among Administrators and calculating the expenses of the project
- Reduced past due Accounts Receivables by \$2.4M utilizing cash management reconciliation, payment negotiations, invoicing and collection calls
- Excelled in a Financial Rotation Program managing an \$18M equipment finance portfolio requiring customer service, account reconciliations, past due
 payment collections and cash posting for new and existing customers while taking sole responsibility for clearing suspense payments for the
 company's \$250B portfolio.